好吗?
OK?
好的。
OK.
——好吗?-好，我再来一次。
- OK? - Yeah, I'll start again.
还是老样子。
Same slate still running.
割喉者。
Cutthroat.
继续跑，会好起来的。从头再来。一样的记录。
Keep running. It'll get better. Start all over again. Same slate.
好吧，瑞克，你想玩什么把戏？
OK, Rick, what's the game?
——割喉者。-目标是什么?
- Cutthroat. - The object is?
目的是让你的蛋蛋在桌子上，然后把其他人的蛋蛋打飞。
The object is to keep your balls on the table and knock everybody else's off.
你还在吗?
You're still there, huh?
我们再唱一首歌就够了。
We're gonna do one more song and that's it.
好吧。
All right.
感恩节快乐。
And happy Thanksgiving.
♪好了，宝贝，别这样别这样别这样别让我心碎求你，别这样，别让我心碎
♪ Well, baby, don't you do it ♪ Don't do it ♪ Don't you break my heart ♪ Please, don't do it, don't you break my heart
♪♪我最大的错误就是太爱你♪♪现在你让我到了你想要的地方♪♪你不会让我走♪♪如果我的心是玻璃做的那么，你一定会明白
♪ My biggest mistake was loving you too much ♪ And letting ya know ♪ Now you got me where you want me ♪ And you won't let me go ♪ if my heart was made of glass ♪ Well, then you'd surely see
♪心痛和悲伤♪♪是你让我心碎♪♪我也一直尽力♪♪别这样别伤我的心♪求你别这样别伤我的心
♪ Heartaches and misery ♪ You been causin♪ me ♪ And I been trying to do my best ♪ You know I try to do my best ♪ Don't do it ♪ Don't you break my heart ♪ Please don't do it ♪ Don't you break my heart
-非常感谢。——谢谢。
- Thank you very much. - Thank you.
晚安，各位。再见。
Good night. Goodbye.
好,看。我们在一起16年了。
OK, look. We've been together 16 years.
——谁?——谁?
- Who? - Who?
乐队。
The Band.
-要我把它插进去吗?-我们再来一次。
- You want me to plug that in? - Let's do it again.
乐队已经在一起16年了。
The Band has been together 16 years.
一起在路上。
Together on the road.
我们在酒吧，潜水，舞厅待了八年。
We did eight years in bars, dives, dance halls.
八年的音乐会，体育场，竞技场。
Eight years of concerts and stadiums, arenas.
我们举办了最后一场音乐会，乐队的最后一场音乐会，我们称之为《最后的华尔兹》。
We gave our final concert, The Band's final concert, and we called it The Last Waltz.
为什么要在旧金山，在温特兰举办，而你们已经在路上奔波了16年?
Why was it held in San Francisco, in Winterland, when you guys have been on the road for 16 years?
温特兰是乐队扮演“乐队”的第一个地方。
Winterland was the first place that the band played as The Band.
一些朋友来了，帮我们把它带回家。
Some friends showed up and helped us take it home.
不只是朋友。他们不止于此。
Not just friends. They're more than that.
你能再问我一次吗?
Would you ask me that again?
他们不只是朋友。他们不只是来打招呼的朋友。
They weren't just friends. They weren't just friends who came in to say hello.
你明白我的意思吗?能飞!
You know what I mean? Get that fly!
不。他们不仅仅是朋友。
No. They were more than just friends.
我觉得他们可能是对整个一代人音乐影响最大的人之一。
I feel they're probably some of the greatest influences on music on a whole generation.
我们想让它不仅仅是一场音乐会。我们想让它成为一场庆典。
We wanted it to be more than just a concert. We wanted it to be a celebration.
庆祝开始还是结束?
Celebration of a beginning or an end?
开始，开始，结束，开始。
Beginning of the beginning of the end of the beginning.
晚上好。
Good evening.
♬你知道我要去哪里吗?
♪ When I get off of this mountain ♪ You know where I wanna go?
♬沿着密西西比河直下到墨西哥湾♬到路易斯安那州的查尔斯湖♬小贝茜，我曾经认识的女孩。她告诉我，如果有什么需要，尽管来找我
♪ Straight down the Mississippi river to the Gulf of Mexico ♪ To Lake Charles, Louisiana ♪ Little Bessie, girl that I once knew ♪ She told me just to come on by if there's anything she could do
♪♪在克里普尔河上，如果我漏水了，她就给我♬，她帮我♬我不用说话，她为我辩护♪一个醉汉的梦，如果我真的看到过
♪ up on Cripple Creek she sends me ♪ if I spring a leak, she mends me ♪ I don't have to speak, she defends me ♪ A drunkard's dream if I ever did see one
♪♪好了，现在我和我的伙伴回到了木屋♪♪我们有斯派克·琼斯坐在包厢里♪她说“我不能接受他唱歌的方式但我喜欢听他说话”
♪ Well, now me and my mate were back at the shack ♪ We had Spike Jones on the box ♪ She said "I can't take the way he sings but I love to hear him talk"
♬在这广阔的世界上有一件事我很想看到♬那就是我的小甜心把她的甜甜圈放进我的茶里♬我要去克里普尔河，是她让我去的
♪ Now there's one thing in the whole wide world I sure do love to see ♪ That's how that little sweet thing of mine puts her doughnut in my tea ♪ I'm going up on Cripple Creek, she sends me
♪♪如果我漏水了，她替我修补♪♪我不用说话，她替我辩护♪一个醉汉的梦，如果我曾经见过
♪ if I spring a leak, she mends me ♪ I don't have to speak, she defends me ♪ A drunkard's dream, if I ever did see one
♪♪加州洪水泛滥，再往北，又冷又冷♪在马路外生活已经太老了♪所以我想我会打电话给我妈妈♪告诉她我会回来的
♪ There's a flood out in California and up north it's freezing cold ♪ And this living off of the road is getting pretty old ♪ So I guess I'll call up my big mama ♪ And tell her I'll be rolling in
♪但你知道吗，内心深处，我有点想再去看我的贝茜♪我要去克里普克里克河，如果我漏水了，她会叫我♪，她会帮我修补♪我不用说话，她会为我辩护
♪ But you know, deep down, I'm sort of tempted ♪ To go and see my Bessie again ♪ I'm going up on Cripple Creek, she sends me ♪ if I spring a leak, she mends me ♪ I don't have to speak, she defends me
♬这是醉汉的梦，如果我曾见过的话
♪ A drunkard's dream if I ever did see one
♬不，不，不，不。♬不，不，不。♬不，不，不
♪ Oh, no, oooh-oooh-oooh ♪ Yodel yodel yodel oooh-oooh ♪ Oh, no, oooh-oooh-oooh ♪ Yodel yodel yodel oooh-oooh ♪ Oh, no, no, no, no ♪ Yodel yodel yodel oooh-oooh ♪ Oh, no, oooh-oooh-oooh
♪♪约德尔约德尔约德尔♪♪♪约德尔约德尔约德尔♪♪约德尔约德尔约德尔♪♪约德尔约德尔约德尔♪♪约德尔约德尔约德尔约德尔♪♪哦，不，哦，哦
♪ Yodel yodel yodel oooh-oooh ♪ Yeah, yeah, you know, I sure wish I could yodel, I know ♪ Yodely, yodely, yodely-oh ♪ Yodel yodel yodel oooh-oooh ♪ Oh, no, oooh-oooh-oooh ♪ Yodel yodel yodel oooh
有点…我们不知道我们要去哪里，我们不知道那是什么。
It was kind of... We didn't know where we were going, we didn't know what it was.
但是，出于某种原因，这似乎是个好主意。
But, for some reason, it seemed like a good idea.
我们到了这个地方，得克萨斯州沃斯堡的一家酒吧。
We got to this place, a joint, in Fort Worth, Texas.
它被烧毁了，被炸毁了。屋顶都没了。
It was burned out, bombed out. The roof wasn't even on the place any more.
就在那时，他们决定把它命名为天际线休息室。
And that's when they decided to call it the Skyline Lounge.
我们到了那里，准备好了……一个大的地方。
And we got there and set up and... A big place.
巨大的。吧台，在后面还有个大舞池。
Huge. Bar, way at the back and a big dance floor.
——真正的老了。-所以我们安排了第一晚。
- Real old. - So we set up the first night.
我们去那个地方玩。
We go down to the place to play.
我们进去，在这个巨大的地方，观众席里大概有三个人。
We go in and, in this huge place, there's about three people in the audience.
一个独臂摇摆舞舞者和几个醉醺醺的服务员。
A one-armed go-go dancer and a couple of drunk waiters.
-这里有几个，那里有几个。-有人发射了催泪弹…一场战斗开始了。
- A couple here, a couple there. - Somebody fires a tear gas... And a fight starts.
这里没有足够的人来生气。
There isn't enough people in the place to get angry.
几年后我们发现那是杰克·鲁比的俱乐部。
And we found out a few years later that it was Jack Ruby's club.
♪走出去，宁静的山谷♪进城来，在巷子里隆隆作响♪哦，你不知道我的处境
♪ Go out yonder, peace in the valley ♪ Come downtown, have to rumble in the alley ♪ Oh, you don't know the shape I'm in
♬有人看见我的小姐吗?
♪ Has anybody seen my lady?
♪哦，你不知道我现在的样子
♪ This living alone will drive me crazy ♪ Oh, you don't know the shape I'm in
♪♪我刚跳进水里♪♪但我不会跳进水里，不，不♪♪我只是在寻找我的造物主♪我听说她就去那里了?哦!
♪ I just been down by the water ♪ But I ain't gonna jump in, no, no ♪ I'll just be looking for my maker ♪ And I hear that's where she's gone? Oh!
♬九次生命中，我度过了七次。你究竟怎样才能上天堂?
♪ Out of nine lives, I spent seven ♪ Now how in the world do you get to heaven?
♪哦，你不知道我现在的样子
♪ Oh, you don't know the shape I'm in
♬我刚在监狱里待了60天♬就因为我没钱♬现在我又回到街头了♬就因为我无处可去♬要么救你的命，要么救你弟弟
♪ Well, I just spent 60 days in the jailhouse ♪ For the crime of having no dough ♪ Now here I am back out on the street ♪ For the crime of having nowhere to go ♪ Save your neck or save your brother
♪♪看起来不是这一条就是那一条哦，你不知道我现在的样子
♪ Looks like it's one or the other ♪ Oh, you don't know the shape I'm in
16年前，当我们开始的时候，我们从一个你可能听说过的人开始。
16 years ago, when we started, we started with a guy you might have heard of.
我们想从他开始。鹰!罗尼·霍金斯!
We'd like to start with him. The Hawk! Ronnie Hawkins!
他打电话给我，我说:“我当然想要一份工作。”这是什么意思?我该怎么办?”
He called me up and I said "Sure I'd like a job. What does it mean? What do I do?"
他说"你赚不了多少钱但你会得到比辛纳屈更多的女人"
He said "You won't make much money but you'll get more pussy than Sinatra."
♬波·迪德利，波·迪德利，你听说了吗?
♪ Bo Diddley, Bo Diddley, have you heard?
♬宝宝会给我买一只知更鸟
♪ Baby's gonna buy me a mockingbird
大日子,比尔!大日子
Big time, Bill! Big time! Big time!
♬我走过了47英里的带刺铁丝网，用一条眼镜蛇做领带♬在路边有一座崭新的房子，用响尾蛇皮做的♬在上面有一个崭新的烟囱，用人的头骨做的
♪ I walked 47 miles of barbed wire, use a cobra snake for a necktie ♪ Got a brand-new house on the roadside, made from rattlesnake hide ♪ Got a brand-new chimney made on top, made from a human skull
来吧，Robbie，我们散个步，告诉我你爱谁?
♪ Come on, Robbie, let's take a little walk, tell me who do you love?
♬你爱谁?
♪ Who do you love?
阿琳拉着我的手说:“你是谁，里基?”我明白了”
♪ Arlene took me by the hand, says "Who are you, Ricky? I understand"
♬你爱谁?
♪ Who do you love?
啊!
Argh!
Arrrgh !
Arrrgh!
Arrrrrrgh !
Arrrrrrgh!
Arrggghhh !
Arrggghhh!
加油,Robbie !
Come on, Robbie!
♪♪我已经41岁了，我不介意死亡
♪ I got a tombstone hand and a graveyard mind ♪ I've turned 41, I don't mind dyin'
♬你爱谁?
♪ Who do you love?
♪♪我骑着马在县里转悠，用响尾蛇鞭♪悠着点，加斯，别给我嘴♪你爱的是谁?
♪ I ride around the county and use a rattlesnake whip ♪ Take it easy, Garth, don't you give me no lip ♪ Who do you love?
♬你爱谁?
♪ Who do you love?
♪♪夜黑夜蓝♪♪街角一辆运冰车飞驰♪撞到了车，有人尖叫，你应该听到我所看到的♪♪你爱谁?
♪ The night was black and the night was blue ♪ Round the corner an ice wagon flew ♪ Bump was hit and somebody screamed, you shoulda heard just what I seen ♪ Who do you love?
♬你爱谁?
♪ Who do you love?
啊!
Argh!
Arrrgh !
Arrrgh!
Arrrrrrgh !
Arrrrrrgh!
Arrrggghhh !
Arrrggghhh!
谢谢你,罗尼!
Thank you, Ronnie!
鹰!
The Hawk!
一周过去了，有点令人沮丧。
And the week went on and it was a little depressing.
尤其令人沮丧的是，我们一分钱都没有。没有面团。
And it was especially depressing cos we didn't have any money at all. No dough.
在某一时刻，我们没有更多的食物钱。
At one point, we had no more food money.
后来，我们从加拿大引进了这种大衣，那种有口袋什么的大大衣，我们有一些常规。
It got to the point where, coming from Canada, we had these overcoats, big overcoats with pockets and everything, and we had a little routine.
我们一起去购物中心。
We'd go to the shopping centre, all together.
-但我待在家里，对吧?-不，你没有。
- But I stayed home, right? - No, you didn't.
我买了香烟。
I got the cigarettes.
我把烟机倒过来给每个人都拿了香烟。
I turned the cigarette machine upside down and got everybody some cigarettes.
-是的，但那是在…-你给我弄了点熏肠。
- Yeah, but that was on the... - You got me some baloney.
我们会去超市，几个人会买几块面包，因为那是你能买到的最便宜的东西。
We'd go to the supermarket and a couple of people would buy a couple of loaves of bread, cos that was about the cheapest thing you could get.
而我们其他人则会在过道里狂欢，填满香肠。
And the rest of us would be carousing the aisles, stuffing baloney.
到了该走的时候，拿面包的人会走到收银台，我们会说:“我们在车上等你。”你把面包拿出来。”
It'd be time to leave, the guy with the loaves would go to the checkout and we'd say "We'll meet you at the car. You take the bread out."
-你会回来的!-有了这些大衣…
- Ya'll come back! - And with these overcoats...
♪我无法忘记你，火焰还在燃烧
♪ And it makes no difference where I turn ♪ I can't get over you and the flame still burns
♪影子似乎永远不会消失♪太阳也不再照耀
♪ And it makes no difference, night or day ♪ The shadow never seems to fade away ♪ And the sun don't shine any more
♪雨落在我的门上
♪ And the rains fall down on my door
♪这些旧情书♪我不能留着♪因为，就像赌徒说的念出来然后哭♪黎明也不会再救我了
♪ Well, these old love letters ♪ Well, I just can't keep them ♪ Cos, like the gambler says ♪ Read 'em and weep ♪ And the dawn don't rescue me no more
♪♪没有你的爱，我将一无所有♪♪就像空荡荡的大厅，寂寞的坠落
♪ Without your love I have nothing at all ♪ Like an empty hall, it's a lonely fall
♪♪自从你走了，这是一场注定失败的战斗♪牛群狂奔，使墙壁嘎嘎作响♪太阳也不再闪耀
♪ Since you've been gone, it's a losing battle ♪ Stampeding cattle they rattle the walls ♪ And the sun don't shine any more
♪雨落在我的门上
♪ And the rains fall down on my door
♪我是如此爱你♪我所能做的只是不让自己告诉你♪我从未感到如此孤独
♪ Well, I love you so much ♪ And it's all I can do ♪ Just to keep myself from telling you ♪ That I never felt so alone before
公羊有他的半蹄，公鹅也有他的半蹄，公鹅也有他的半蹄，整夜睁着眼睛睡觉——这样就把大自然刺进他的马车;
Hath in the Ram his halfe cours yronne, And smale foweles maken melodye, That slepen al the nyght with open eye- So priketh hem Nature in hir corages;
向ferne halwes，在sondry londes磕头;
Thanne longen folk to goon on pilgrimages To ferne halwes, kowthe in sondry londes;
特别是从恩格尔隆德的每一个郡，到坎特伯雷，他们都在为他们所寻找的人，祈祷着神圣而又幸福的祈祷
And specially from every shires ende Of Engelond, to Caunterbury they wende, The hooly blisful martir for the seke That hem hath holpen, whan that they were seeke
迈克尔·麦克卢尔!
Michael McClure!
你们都认识约翰医生吗?
You all know Doctor John?
Mac Rebennack。来吧,Mac。
Mac Rebennack. Come on, Mac.
感谢乐队和所有的人。
In thankfulness to The Band and all the fellas.
二、三、四、一……
Two, three, four, one...
♬这样的夜晚
♪ Such a night
♪月光下甜蜜的迷茫
♪ Sweet confusion ♪ under the moonlight
♬这样的夜晚
♪ Such a night
♪♪该偷走了♪时机似乎正对
♪ Got to steal away ♪ The time seems right
♪当你我的目光相遇
♪ When your eyes met mine
♬概览
♪ At a glance
♪♪你让我知道♪♪这是我的机会♪♪你和我最好的朋友吉姆一起进来♪看，我总想把你从他身边偷走♪哦，宝贝，如果我不这么做，别人会这么做
♪ You let me know ♪ This was my chance ♪ You came in with my best friend Jim ♪ See I aim da-da-da to steal you away from him ♪ Oh, baby, if I don't do it, somebody else will
♪。我不做，别人会♪。我不做，别人会♪。我不做，别人会♪
♪ if I don't do it, somebody else will ♪ if I don't do it, somebody else will ♪ if I don't do it, somebody else will ♪ Such a night
♬这样的夜晚
♪ Such a night
♪月光下甜蜜的迷茫
♪ Sweet confusion ♪ under the moonlight
♬这样的夜晚
♪ Such a night
♪。只能偷偷溜走
♪ Got to steal away
♬时机似乎正对。宝贝，我不敢相信自己的耳朵
♪ The time seems right ♪ Baby, I couldn't believe my ears
♪♪你告诉我我们可以偷偷溜走♪♪亲爱的，你和我最好的朋友吉姆一起走进来
♪ My heart just skipped a little beat ♪ You told me we could slip away ♪ Down the dark end of the street ♪ Baby, you came in with my best friend Jim
♪♪看，我的目标就是把你从他身边偷走♪如果我不做，就会有人会♪♪如果我不做，就会有人会♪♪如果我不做，就会有人会
♪ See, I aim da-da-da to steal you away from him, baby ♪ if I don't do it, somebody else will ♪ if I don't do it, you know somebody else will ♪ if I don't do it, somebody else will
♪。如果我不做，别人会做的
♪ if I don't do it, somebody else will
嘿!
Hey!
医生!
The Doctor!
每个人都知道他。
Everybody knows him.
我打赌你认识这个人。
You know this guy, I bet.
-谢谢你让我这么做。——哦,大便。你在开玩笑吧?
- Thank you, man, for letting me do this. - Oh, shit. Are you kidding?
你在开玩笑吧?
Are you kidding?
在我开始之前，我想说今晚能和这些人一起站在舞台上，是我生命中最快乐的事情之一。
I'd just like to say before I start that it's one of the pleasures of my life to be able to be on the stage with these people tonight.
他们现在知道了，Robbie。
They got it now, Robbie.
在安大略省北部有一个小镇
♪ There is a town in north Ontario
♪留着梦幻般的温馨回忆
♪ With dream-comfort memories to spare
♪心里还是需要一个地方去
♪ In my mind I still need a place to go
♪我所有的改变都在那里
♪ All my changes were there
♪蓝色，星星后面蓝色的窗户
♪ Blue, blue windows behind the stars
♬黄色的月亮在升起
♪ Yellow moon on the rise
♬飞过天空的大鸟
♪ The big birds flying across the sky
♪♪他们在我们的眼中投下阴影♪♪无奈，无奈，无奈♪你让我感到如此无助好了，宝贝，你现在能听到我说话吗?
♪ They were throwing shadows on our eyes ♪ Leave us ♪ Helpless, helpless, helpless ♪ You make me feel so helpless ♪ Well, baby, can you hear me now?
♬我现在能听到你的声音了
♪ I can hear you now ♪ The chains are locked and tied across my door
但是，宝贝，宝贝，不管怎样，和我一起唱
♪ But, baby, baby, sing with me somehow
♪蓝色，星星后面蓝色的窗户
♪ Blue, blue windows behind the stars
♬黄色的月亮在升起
♪ Yellow moon on the rise
♬飞过天空的大鸟
♪ The big birds flying across the sky
♪♪他们在我们的眼中投下阴影留给我们♪无奈，无奈，无奈
♪ They're throwing shadows on our eyes ♪ Leave us ♪ Helpless, helpless, helpless
♪无奈，无奈，无奈
♪ Helpless, helpless, helpless
♬宝贝，现在你能听到我吗?
♪ Helpless, helpless, helpless ♪ Baby, can you hear me now?
♪无奈，无奈，无奈
♪ Helpless, helpless, helpless
♪无奈，无奈，无奈♪爱你的人，爱你的人，爱你的人，爱你的人，爱你的人，爱你的人，爱你的人，爱你的人
♪ Helpless, helpless, helpless ♪ Chains are locked and tied ♪ Helpless, helpless, helpless ♪ Baby, baby, baby, sing with me somehow - ♪ Helpless, helpless, helpless - ♪ With me somehow
♪无奈，无奈，无奈
♪ Helpless, helpless, helpless
尼尔年轻!
Neil Young!
我不知道这是什么。也许是时间联系，或者只是巧合，但似乎就是这样。
I don't know what it is. Maybe the years connect or it's coincidence, but it seems like that's it.
这就是《最后的华尔兹》。
That's what The Last Waltz is.
我是说，在路上奔波了16年。这些数字开始让你感到害怕。
I mean, 16 years on the road. The numbers start to scare you.
我不能在路上流浪20年。
I couldn't live with 20 years on the road.
我觉得我都不能说。
I don't think I could even discuss it.
♬这是一个孤独的孩子的内心深处他为自己所做的一切承受了那么多的痛苦是他们给了这个可怜的孩子财富和名声♬从那一天起，他就变了
♪ Now deep in the heart of a lonely kid ♪ Who suffered so much for what he did ♪ They gave this poor boy his fortune and fame ♪ Since that day he ain't been the same
♪♪看那个怯场的男人♪♪只是站在那里全力以赴♪♪他被聚光灯照到♪但当我们走到终点他想从头再来
♪ See the man with the stage fright ♪ Just standing up there to give it all his might ♪ He got caught in the spotlight ♪ But when we get to the end ♪ He wants to start all over again
♬我的呼吸中有烈酒♬医生警告我，我可能会死♬他说"你可以伪装自己"
♪ I've got firewater right on my breath ♪ And the doctor warned me I might catch a death ♪ He said "You can make it in your disguise"
♬永远不要流露出恐惧的眼神
♪ "Just never show the fear in your eyes"
♪♪看那个怯场的男人♪♪只是站在那里全力以赴♪♪他被聚光灯照到♪但当我们走到终点他想从头再来
♪ See the man with the stage fright ♪ Just standing up there to give it all his might ♪ He got caught in the spotlight ♪ But when we get to the end ♪ He wants to start all over again
♪现在当他说他害怕♪你不会相信他的话吗?
♪ Now when he says that he's afraid ♪ Won't you take him at his word?
♬这可怜的孩子付出的代价♬他可以像鸟儿一样唱歌♬噢噢噢噢噢噢
♪ And for the price that the poor boy has paid ♪ Well, he gets to sing just like a bird ♪ Oooh oooh oooh-oooh
♬我的额头在冒汗，我的嘴在干♬那些幻想的人在游荡♬好吧，关键时刻就在眼前♬又一个你能忍受的噩梦♬看看那个怯场的男人
♪ My brow is sweating and my mouth gets dry ♪ The fancy people go drifting by ♪ Well, the moment of truth is right at hand ♪ Just one more nightmare you can stand ♪ See the man with the stage fright
♪♪只是站在那里拼尽全力♪♪然后他就成了镁光♪♪但当我们走到终点他想从头再来不，不，不♪对了，让他重新开始
♪ Just standing up there to give it all his might ♪ And he got caught in the spotlight ♪ But when we get to the end ♪ Well, he wants to start all over again, no, no, no ♪ That's right, make him start
♬让他从头再来
♪ Just let him take it from the top
我们是老鹰队。
Well, we were The Hawks.
一切都很好。我们在航行。
Everything was fine. We were sailing along.
突然，有一天，老鹰队的意义完全改变了。
And all of a sudden, one day, The Hawks meant something else altogether.
就在那个迷幻药的中心。
It was right in the middle of that whole psychedelia.
“巧克力地铁”。“棉花糖大衣”。这样的名字。
"Chocolate Subway". "Marshmallow Overcoat". Those kind of names.
当我们和鲍勃·迪伦合作，搬到伍德斯托克时，每个人都叫我们“乐队”。
When we were working with Bob Dylan and we moved to Woodstock, everybody referred to us as The Band.
他叫我们乐队。我们的朋友和邻居都叫我们乐队。
He called us The Band. Our friends and neighbours called us The Band.
我们从《饼干侠》开始。
And we started out with The Crackers.
我们试着叫自己白佬。
We tried to call ourselves The Honkies.
每个人都不这么想，你知道吗?
Everybody kind of backed off from that, you know?
太直了。
It was too straight.
所以我们决定称自己为乐队。
So we decided just to call ourselves The Band.
♪♪我驶入了拿撒勒，感觉自己已经半死♪只需要找个地方让自己安睡♪“先生，你能告诉我哪里能找到床吗?”
♪ I pulled into Nazareth just feeling 'bout half-past dead ♪ Just need to find a place where I can lay my head ♪ "Mister, can you tell me where a man might find a bed?"
♬他只是笑笑，握了握我的手。♬这就是他说的♬“放一放范妮”♬“放一放范妮”♬还有……♪你把重担都压在我身上
♪ He just grinned and shook my hand ♪ "No! '♪ was all he said ♪ Take a load off Fanny ♪ Take a load for free ♪ Take a load off Fanny ♪ And... ♪ You put the load right on me
♪♪当我看到老卡门和魔鬼并肩而行，我说:“嘿，卡门，来吧，我们去市中心。”
♪ I picked up my bag and went looking for a place to hide ♪ When I saw old Carmen and the Devil walking side by side ♪ I said "Hey, Carmen, come on, let's go downtown"
♬她说:“我得走了，但我的朋友可以留下来。”
♪ She said "I gotta go but my friend can stick around"
♪抽一根烟♪抽一根烟♪还有…♪你把重担都压在我身上
♪ Take a load off Fanny ♪ Take a load for free ♪ Take a load off Fanny ♪ And... ♪ You put the load right on me
♪♪下去，摩西，没什么可说的♪♪只是老路加和路加在等待审判日♪嘿，路加，我的朋友，年轻的安娜·李怎么样?
♪ Go down, Moses, there's nothin♪ that you can say ♪ It's just old Luke and Luke is waiting on the Judgment Day ♪ "Hey, Luke, my friend, what about young Anna Lee?"
♬他说:“帮我个忙，孩子。”
♪ He said "Do me a favour, son"
“你留下来陪安娜·李好吗?”
"Won't you stay and keep Anna Lee company?"
♪抽一根烟♪抽一根烟♪还有…♪你把重担都压在我身上
♪ Take a load off Fanny ♪ Take a load for free ♪ Take a load off Fanny ♪ And... ♪ You put the load right on me
♬疯狂的切斯特跟着我，他在雾中抓住了我。他说:“如果你带我的狗老杰克去，我就给你修好。”
♪ Crazy Chester followed me and he caught me in the fog ♪ He said "I will fix your rack if you take old Jack, my dog"
我说:“等一下，切斯特，你知道我是个爱好和平的人。”
♪ I said "Wait a minute, Chester, you know I'm a peaceful man"
♬他说:“没关系，孩子，你能不能随时喂它?”
♪ He said "That's OK, boy, won't you feed him whenever you can"
♪抽一根烟♪抽一根烟♪还有…♪你把重担都压在我身上
♪ Take a load off Fanny ♪ Take a load for free ♪ Take a load off Fanny ♪ And... ♪ You put the load right on me
♪♪我的背包越来越低我相信是时候回到范妮小姐身边了，你知道她是我的唯一
♪ Catch a cannonball now to take me on down the line ♪ My bag is sinking low and I do believe that it's time ♪ To get back to Miss Fanny, you know she's the only one
♬她让我来这儿是为大家着想。♬放心吧，范妮。♬放心吧，范妮
♪ She sent me here with regards for everyone ♪ Take a load off Fanny ♪ Take a load for free ♪ Take a load off Fanny ♪ And you put the load right on me
♪哦，范妮，放轻松点
♪ Oh, Fanny, take a load off Fanny
♪呵呵
♪ Ohhh
漂亮!
Beautiful!
-那不需要打扫吗?-这看起来很有趣。
- Doesn't that need dusting? - This looks interesting.
我们为大家演奏《旧时代的宗教》
We'll play "Old-Time Religion" for the folks.
♪♪旧时代的宗教，给我那个旧时代的宗教♪这就够了♪这就够了♪这对爷爷好，对奶奶好♪这就够了♪好了，现在够了
♪ Old-time religion, give me that old-time religion ♪ And it's good enough ♪ Well, it's good enough ♪ It was good for Grandpa, good for my grandma ♪ It's good enough ♪ Good enough, good enough now
哦，跟以前不一样了!
Oh, it's not like it used to be!
♪♪我叫维吉尔·凯恩我在丹维尔的火车上服役♪♪直到斯通曼的骑兵来了，他们又把铁轨给毁了65年的冬天，我们饿得奄奄一息
♪ Virgil Caine is the name and I served on the Danville train ♪ Till Stoneman's cavalry came and they tore up the tracks again ♪ In the winter of '65 we were hungry, just barely alive
♪♪到5月10日里士满陷落♪那是我记忆犹新的一段时光♪那一晚他们把老迪克西送过来♪当所有的钟声都响起♪那一晚他们把老迪克西送过来
♪ By May the tenth Richmond had fell ♪ It's a time I remember oh so well ♪ The night they drove old Dixie down ♪ When all the bells were ringing ♪ The night they drove old Dixie down
♪。所有的人都在唱♪。他们就这样啦啦啦啦啦啦。♪
♪ And all the people were singing ♪ They went la la-la la la-la laaa ♪ La la-la la la-la la-la laaa
♪♪我和妻子在田纳西的时候♪♪有一天她呼唤我说“维吉尔，快来看看罗伯特·李走了!”
♪ Back with my wife in Tennessee ♪ When one day she called to me ♪ Said "Virgil, quick, come and see there goes Robert E Lee!"
♪♪现在我不介意砍木头♪♪我也不介意钱不好♪你需要什么就拿走什么剩下的♪但他们不该拿走最好的
♪ Now I don't mind chopping wood ♪ And I don't care if the money's no good ♪ You take what you need and you leave the rest ♪ But they should never have taken the very best
♪♪那晚他们载着老迪克西而来♪所有的人都在唱♪他们一起啦啦啦啦啦
♪ The night they drove old Dixie down ♪ When all the bells were ringing ♪ The night they drove old Dixie down ♪ And all the people were singing ♪ They went la la-la la la-la laaa
♬啦啦啦啦啦
♪ La la-la la la-la la-la laaa
♪♪就像我的父亲一样♪♪就像我的哥哥一样他选择了反抗♪他只有18岁，骄傲而勇敢但是一个美国佬把他埋进了坟墓
♪ Like my father before me ♪ I will work the land ♪ And like my brother above me ♪ Who took a rebel stand ♪ He was just 18, proud and brave ♪ But a Yankee laid him in his grave
♬我对着我脚下的泥土发誓当一个凯恩失败时你不能让他振作起来♬在他们把老迪克西赶走的那个夜晚当所有的钟声响起
♪ And I swear by the mud below my feet ♪ You can't raise a Caine back up when he's in defeat ♪ The night they drove old Dixie down ♪ When all the bells were ringing
♪♪某天晚上他们把老迪克西开过来♪所有的人都在唱♪他们一起啦啦啦啦啦啦啦
♪ The night they drove old Dixie down ♪ And all the people were singing ♪ They went la la-la la la-la laaa ♪ La la-la la la-la la-la laaa
♪♪夜晚他们载着老迪克西过来♪所有的人都在唱♪他们在啦啦啦啦啦啦
♪ The night they drove old Dixie down, down ♪ The bells were ringing ♪ The night they drove old Dixie down ♪ And all the people were singing ♪ They went la la-la la la-la laaa
♬啦啦啦啦啦
♪ La la-la la la-la la-la laaa
美梦成真。
A dream come true.
令人着迷。可怕的。
Fascinating. Scary.
第一次有点难以接受。
Kind of hard to take the first time.
你必须去那里两三次，才能爱上它。
You have to go there about two or three times before you can fall in love with it.
但这最终会发生。
But that happens eventually.
我们住在42街的时代广场酒店。
We stayed at the Times Square Hotel on 42nd Street.
酒店的名字，听起来像是位于曼哈顿市中心。
The title of the hotel, it sounded like it was conveniently located in midtown Manhattan.
我们知道什么?我们登记入住后走出酒店，你会想“回到纽约真好”。
What did we know? We came out of the hotel after checking in, and you think "It's great to be back in New York."
永远的电影院。
Movie theatres for ever.
这些友好的女人在街上走来走去。
All these friendly women walking up and down the street.
……这是伟大的。
It was... It was great.
对，纽约，是成年人的地盘。这是成年人的剂量。
Yeah, New York, it was an adult portion. It was an adult dose.
所以我们花了几次时间才了解它。
So it took a couple of trips to get into it.
你只是第一次进去，然后被揍了一顿，然后就走了。
You just go in the first time and you get your ass kicked and you take off.
一旦伤口愈合，你就会回来再试一次。
As soon as it heals up, you come back and you try it again.
最终，你会爱上它。
Eventually, you fall right in love with it.
轮盘唱片公司就在锡盘巷这个神秘的地方。
Roulette Records was in the middle of this mythical place, Tin Pan Alley.
世界歌曲创作之都。
The songwriting capital of the world.
我们遇到了一些最伟大的词曲作者。
And we met some of the greatest songwriters ever.
摇滚歌曲作者。医生Pomus。莫特舒曼。利和短距起落。
Rock-and-roll songwriters. Doc Pomus. Mort Shuman. Lieber and Stoller.
他们当时都是。卡罗尔的国王。尼尔钻石。
They were all then. Carole King. Neil Diamond.
在那个时候，一个词曲作家处于最底层是不公平的。
At the time it wasn't fair that a songwriter was the low man on the totem pole.
但是，这些人……到了60年代，伴随着变革、革命、战争和暗杀，一种全新的思维模式也随之出现。
But then, these people... And here come the '60s, with change and revolution and war and assassinations, and a whole other frame of mind coming along.
这些词曲作者在街头表达人们的情感。
And these songwriters were expressing the feelings of people in the street.
在某种程度上，这是锡盘巷尽头的开始。
In a way, it was kind of the beginning of the end of Tin Pan Alley.
♬擦干眼泪♬把你的歌拿出来♬这是一个新生的下午♬如果你想不起歌手♬你还能记得那首曲子吗?
♪ Dry your eyes ♪ Take your song out ♪ It's a newborn afternoon ♪ And if you can't recall the singer ♪ Can you still recall the tune?
♪擦干眼泪♪慢慢唱就像你要奔赴战场♪唱就像你一直想唱的♪就像你曾经唱过的
♪ Dry your eyes ♪ And play it slowly ♪ Just like you're marching off to war ♪ Sing it like you always wanted ♪ Like you sung it once before
♪♪从圆圈的中心到等待的人群中间♪♪长长唱吧，大声唱吧♪来吧，擦干你的眼泪
♪ And from the centre of the circle ♪ To the midst of the waiting crowd ♪ if it ever is forgotten ♪ Sing it long and sing it loud ♪ And come dry your eyes
♪♪他教会了我们更多关于生活的东西♪♪我们学会了这个秘密♪我们永不放弃
♪ And he taught us more about living ♪ Than we ever cared to know ♪ And we came to learn the secret ♪ And we never let it go
♬这比神圣多了♪虽然比自由少了♪如果你想不起理由你能听到人们的歌声吗?
♪ And it was more than being holy ♪ Though it was less than being free ♪ And if you can't recall the reason ♪ Can you hear the people sing?
♬穿过电闪雷鸣♬通往月亮黑暗的一面♬通往遥远的堕落天使♬那堕落得太快♬来吧，擦干你的眼泪
♪ Right through the lightning and the thunder ♪ To the dark side of the moon ♪ To that distant falling angel ♪ That descended much too soon ♪ Come dry your eyes
♪擦干你的眼泪♪把你的歌拿出来♪这是一个新生的下午♪如果你想不起歌手♪你还能回忆起那首歌♪来擦干你的眼泪
♪ Dry your eyes ♪ Take your song out ♪ It's a newborn afternoon ♪ And if you can't recall the singer ♪ You can still recall the tune ♪ Come dry your eyes
来擦干你的眼泪
♪ Come dry your eyes
♬擦干眼泪
♪ Dry your eyes
尼尔钻石!
Neil Diamond!
非常感谢。
Thanks very much.
当你开始作为乐队的一员演奏时，你总是避开公众的视线。
When you started playing as The Band, you shied away from publicity a lot.
谈谈这个。
Talk about that a little.
这只是我们在伍德斯托克喜欢的生活方式的一部分。
That was just part of a lifestyle that we got to love in Woodstock.
我们会喜欢它的，你知道，只是能够砍木头或用锤子打你的拇指。
We got to like it, you know, just being able to chop wood or hit your thumb with a hammer.
我们只关心修理录音机，修理纱门。
We'd be concerned with fixing a tape recorder, fixing a screen door.
诸如此类。然后把歌曲收集起来。
Stuff like that. And getting the songs together.
当我们周围没有很多人的时候，我们似乎总是能做得更多。
We always seemed to get a whole lot more done when we didn't have a lot of company around.
我们的工作效率更高。
We were more productive.
当然，只要有客人来，我们就会开始玩得很开心。
And as soon as company came, of course, we'd start having fun.
你知道你玩得太开心会发生什么。
You know what happens when you have too much fun.
我们一直在回避的问题，但我现在就问。
Something we've kind of evaded around here, but I'll ask it now.
-那女人和公路呢?-我喜欢。
- What about women and the road? - I love 'em.
也许这就是我们一直在路上的原因。
That's probably why we've been on the road.
——就是这样。-不是我不喜欢这音乐。
- That's it. - Not that I don't like the music.
我以为你不应该谈论太多。
I thought you weren't supposed to talk about it too much.
-不，我想我们没有。-我以为我们应该远离那些东西，去做点别的。
- No, I guess we're not. - I thought we were supposed to... pan away from that sort of stuff, get into something else.
从一开始，自从我们开始一起玩，就像我们都成长了一点点，女人们也一样。
Since the beginning, since we started playing together, just like we've all grown just a little bit, so have the women.
——你知道吗?和令人惊奇的。——这是正确的。这很好。
- You know? And it's amazing. - That's right. That's good.
我只想收支平衡。
I just wanna break even.
乔妮·米切尔。正确的。
Joni Mitchell. Right.
♬我不后悔，土狼♬我们只是来自不同的环境。♬我在演播室整夜不睡，而你在农场很早就起床
♪ No regrets, coyote ♪ We just come from such different sets of circumstance ♪ I'm up all night in the studios and you're up early on your ranch
♬你会在太阳升起的时候给母马梳洗尾巴而我只会带着我的卷轴回家不明白
♪ You'll be brushing out a brood mare's tail while the sun is ascending ♪ And I'll just be getting home with my reel-to-reel ♪ There's no comprehending
♪♪就像骨头、皮肤、眼睛还有嘴唇，你能摸到♪♪还是觉得那么孤单还是觉得彼此有关联♪就像某个中继站
♪ Just how close to the bone and the skin and the eyes ♪ And the lips you can get ♪ And still feel so alone ♪ And still feel related ♪ Like stations in some relay
♬你不是一个肇事逃逸的司机，不，不♬你只是让别人搭便车♬一个被高速公路白线束缚的人
♪ You're not a hit-and-run driver, no, no ♪ Racing away ♪ You just picked up a hitcher ♪ A prisoner of the white lines on the freeway
我们看见一间农舍被烧毁了♪♪就在半夜，在一个不知名的地方我们径直驶过那个悲剧♪♪直到我们停在一个路边旅馆的灯前
♪ We saw a farmhouse burning down ♪ In the middle of nowhere in the middle of the night ♪ And we rolled right past that tragedy ♪ until we pulled in to some roadhouse lights
♪♪在一个本地乐队演奏的地方♪♪当地人在地板上又踢又抖♪接下来我所知道的是♪那只郊狼就在我家门口♪他把我按在角落里，他不接受我的拒绝
♪ Where a local band was playing ♪ Locals were up kicking and shaking on the floor ♪ The next thing I know ♪ That coyote's at my door ♪ He pins me in the corner and he won't take "No!"
♬他把我拖到舞池里，我们慢慢地靠得很近。♬现在他在家里有了一个女人。♬他在大厅里有了另一个女人，他似乎想要我
♪ He drags me out on the dance floor and we're dancing close and slow ♪ Now he's got a woman at home ♪ He's got another woman down the hall and he seems to want me anyway
为什么你要喝得这么醉，带我走那条路?
♪ Why do you have to get so drunk and lead me on that way?
♬你刚搭了辆便车♬你被高速公路上的白线困住了
♪ You just picked up a hitcher ♪ A prisoner of the white lines on the freeway
♬我看着一只野狼迎面走来♬在去我老家附近的Baljennie的路上他穿过长髯的麦穗跑着♬追逐着奖品♬一只鹰在和他玩耍
♪ I looked a coyote right in the face ♪ On the road to Baljennie, near my old home town ♪ He went running through the whisker wheat ♪ Chasing some prize down ♪ And a hawk was playing with him
他有一双和你一样的眼睛，就像你戴着墨镜的眼睛。♬私下里试探着公共房间
♪ Coyote was jumping straight up and making passes ♪ He had those same eyes, just like yours ♪ under your dark glasses ♪ Privately probing the public rooms
♬从有编号的门上的钥匙孔里窥视。♬在那里，玩家舔着伤口，带走他们暂时的爱人，拿着药丸和粉末，让他们度过这场激情游戏
♪ And peeking through keyholes in numbered doors ♪ Where the players lick their wounds and take their temporary lovers ♪ And their pills and powders to get them through this passion play
♬我不后悔，野狼♬我刚下车♬你刚搭了辆便车♬你是高速公路白线的囚徒
♪ No regrets, coyote ♪ I just get off up aways ♪ You just picked up a hitcher ♪ A prisoner of the white lines on the freeway
♪♪野狼在咖啡店♪♪他盯着炒蛋上的洞♪♪当他看着女服务员的腿时他从手指上闻到了我的气味♪♪他离芬迪湾太远了
♪ Coyote's in the coffee shop ♪ He's staring a hole in his scrambled eggs ♪ He picks up my scent on his fingers while he's watching the waitresses♪ legs ♪ He's too far from the Bay of Fundy
♪♪从阿帕鲁萨斯，老鹰，潮汐♪♪还有空调的小隔间♪还有碳带式的游乐设施都说明了♪♪他要么站起来战斗
♪ From Appaloosas and eagles and tides ♪ And the air-conditioned cubicles ♪ And the carbon ribbon rides are spelling it out so clear ♪ Either he's gonna have to stand and fight
♪♪或者离开这里♪♪我曾试图逃离♪♪想要逃离，与自我搏斗♪用你在爱斯基摩人身上放的火焰♪在这个搭车人身上♪在这个囚犯身上
♪ Or take off out of here ♪ I've tried to run away myself ♪ To run away and wrestle with my ego ♪ And with this flame you put here in this Eskimo ♪ In this hitcher ♪ In this prisoner
♪白色的细线♪白色的细线♪在自由的高速公路上
♪ Of the fine white lines ♪ Of the white lines ♪ On the free freeway
列文的家乡在西海伦娜附近。
Levon's home town, it's near West Helena.
有一次我们去了那里，出于某种原因，我们决定去看看那个小镇的一个传奇人物，那就是桑尼·威廉姆森。
One time we were there, for some reason or another, and we decided we were gonna look up one of the legends of that town, which was Sonny Boy Williamson.
在我看来，他是最好的口琴演奏家，就像口琴，蓝调口琴，这是我听过的。
In my opinion, he's the best harp player, that's like harmonica, blues harmonica, that I've ever heard.
他是他们的老大。
He's the big Daddy of 'em.
他带我们去了他的一个朋友，一个女人的地方，那里供应食物和玉米酒。
And he took us to a friend of his, a woman's place, who served food and corn liquor.
在一个南方的酒罐里。
In a southern booze can.
他会坐在那里为我们演奏。
He would sit there and he was playing for us.
我们喝得酩酊大醉，想弄清楚我们在哪里。
And we were getting drunk and trying to figure out where we were.
他往罐子里吐痰。我以为他在吸鼻烟。
He was spitting in a can. I thought he was dipping snuff.
我以为他嘴唇上有什么东西。
I thought he had something in his lip.
他不停地往罐子里吐痰，玩个不停，我们喝得越来越醉。
And he kept spitting in this can and playing, and we kept getting drunker.
最后，我看了看罐子，发现是血。
Finally, I looked over in the can and I realised it was blood.
那时他已经很累，也很醉了。
He was getting pretty tired and pretty drunk by then.
我们为未来制定了宏伟的计划还有我们要做的所有事情。
And we made big plans for the future and all kinds of things we were gonna do.
这真是太棒了。一个伟大的夜晚。
And it was tremendous. A great night.
几个月后，我们收到了他的经理的来信，信里说他已经去世了。
A couple of months later, we got a letter from his manager, or whoever it was, saying that he had passed away.
♬火车到站长16节
♪ Train arrive ♪ 16 coaches long
♪火车到了，耶♪16节车厢长
♪ Train arrive, yeah ♪ 16 coaches long
♪好吧，那长长的黑色火车载着我的孩子走了
♪ Well, that long, black train took my baby and gone
♬火车，火车，在转弯处滚动
♪ Train, train ♪ Rolling round the bend
♬它又把我的孩子带走了
♪ Well, it took my baby away from me again
♪听到汽笛声响起，那是半夜。♪当我到达车站时，那列火车正驶离我的视线
♪ Heard that whistle blowing, it was the middle of the night ♪ When I got down to the station the train was pulling out of sight ♪ Mystery train ♪ Rolling round the bend
♬神秘的火车♬在转弯处滚动
♪ Mystery train ♪ Rolling round the bend
♪。它又把我的宝贝♪从我身边带走
♪ Well, it took my baby ♪ Away from me again
保罗·巴特菲尔德!
Paul Butterfield!
在孟菲斯附近，有棉花之乡，有水稻之乡，最有趣的可能就是音乐了。
Near Memphis, cotton country, rice country, the most interesting thing is probably the music.
Levon，谁是从那里来的?
Levon, who came from around there?
卡尔珀金斯。
Carl Perkins.
马迪·沃特斯，乡村音乐之王。
Muddy Waters, the king of country music.
猫王。
Elvis Presley.
约翰尼·卡什。波迪德利。
Johnny Cash. Bo Diddley.
那边是美国的中部地区。
That's kind of the middle of the country back there.
所以蓝草音乐或乡村音乐，你知道，如果它进入那个区域，如果它与节奏混合，如果它跳舞，那么你就得到了所有不同类型音乐的结合。
So bluegrass or country music, you know, if it comes down to that area and if it mixes there with rhythm and if it dances, then you've got a combination of all those different kinds of music.
乡村音乐、蓝草音乐、蓝调音乐。
Country, bluegrass, blues music.
-大熔炉-播放音乐
- The melting pot. - Show music.
-叫什么名字?-摇滚!
- And what's it called? - Rock and roll!
是的。完全正确。
Yes. Exactly.
哇!
Whoa!
♪♪当我还是个年轻的男孩五岁时♪我妈妈说我是最伟大的男人♪♪但现在我一个人过去21♪♪方式我希望你相信我,女人♪我有很多乐趣♪我一个人
♪ When I was a young boy ♪ At the age of five ♪ My mother said I would be ♪ The greatest man alive ♪ But now I'm a man ♪ Way past 21 ♪ I want you to believe me, woman ♪ I have lots of fun ♪ I'm a man
♬我拼“M”
♪ I spell "M"
♪“A”,智利
♪ "A", chile
♪“N”
♪ "N"
♬我奶奶说我长大了
♪ My grandma says I'm grown
♪没有“B”
♪ No "B"
♪♪智利♪♪Y
♪ "O", chile ♪ "Y"
♬那个刻薄的男人气男孩
♪ That mean mannish boy
♪♪我是一个成熟的男人♪♪我是一个天生的爱人的男人
♪ Man ♪ I'm a full-grown man ♪ Man ♪ I'm a natural-born lover's man
♪♪我是一块滚石
♪ Man ♪ I'm a rolling stone
♪♪我是个爱吹牛的人
♪ Man ♪ I'm a hoochie-coochie man
♪好
♪ Well
♪好吧，好吧，好吧，行我射
♪ Well, well, well ♪ The line I shoot
♪当我和一个女孩做爱时，我永远不会错过♪
♪ I will never miss ♪ When I make love to a girl
♪♪她无法抗拒♪♪我想我会去♪♪我要带我的二堂兄回来♪那个小强尼康格鲁
♪ She can't resist ♪ I think I'll go down ♪ To old Kansas Stew ♪ I'm gonna bring back my second cousin ♪ That little Johnny Congeroo
♪♪所有的小女孩♪♪坐在这条线外我可以和你做爱，女孩五分钟
♪ All you little girls ♪ Sitting out at that line ♪ I can make love to you, girl ♪ In five minutes♪ time
♬那不是男人吗?
♪ Ain't that a man?
♬我拼“M”
♪ I spell "M"
♪“A”,智利
♪ "A", chile
♪“N”
♪ "N"
♬那代表人类
♪ That represents man
♪没有“B”
♪ No "B"
♪♪智利♪♪Y
♪ "O", chile ♪ "Y"
♬那就是像男人一样的男孩
♪ That means mannish boy
♬我是个成熟的男人
♪ Man ♪ I'm a full-grown man
♪我是天生的情人的男人
♪ Man ♪ I'm a natural-born lover's man
♪♪我是一块滚石
♪ Man ♪ I'm a rolling stone
♬我是个爱哭鬼
♪ Man-child ♪ I'm a hoochie-coochie man
♪♪好、好、好、好、好♪♪好、好、好、好、好
♪ Well ♪ Well, well, well, well, well, well, well ♪ Well, well, well, well, well
那不是一个男人吗?浑水!
Wasn't that a man! Muddy Waters!
弹吉他，埃里克·克莱普顿!
On the guitar, Eric Clapton!
一，二，一，二，三…
One, two, a-one, two, three...
♪♪就在这条路上有人会伤害你，就像你伤害我一样♪♪就在这条路上有人会伤害你，就像你伤害我一样♪♪就在这条路上宝贝，你等着瞧吧
♪ Further on up the road ♪ Someone's gonna hurt you like you hurt me ♪ Further on up the road ♪ Someone's gonna hurt you like you hurt me ♪ Further on up the road ♪ Baby, just you wait and see
♪这句老话说得好，一分耕耘一分收获。♪就像你虐待别人一样，总有一天会有人虐待你
♪ You gotta reap just what you sow ♪ That old saying is true ♪ You gotta reap just what you sow ♪ That old saying is true ♪ Just like you mistreat someone ♪ Someone's gonna mistreat you
总有人会伤害你，就像你伤害我一样总有人会伤害你，就像你伤害我一样总有人会伤害你，就像你伤害我一样总有人会伤害你，就像你伤害我一样总有人会伤害你，就像你伤害我一样总有人会伤害你，就像你伤害我一样总有人会伤害你
♪ Further up the road ♪ Someone's gonna hurt you like you hurt me ♪ Further on up the road ♪ Someone's gonna hurt you like you hurt me ♪ Further on up the road ♪ Baby, just you wait and see
♪你一直在笑，可爱的宝贝总有一天你会哭♪你一直在笑，可爱的宝贝总有一天你会哭♪再往前走你就会发现我没有说谎
♪ You been laughing, pretty baby ♪ Someday you're gonna be crying ♪ You been laughing, pretty baby ♪ Someday you're gonna be crying ♪ Further on up the road ♪ You'll find out I wasn't lying
好的。瑞克，香格里拉是什么?也许你可以带我们参观一下。
OK. So, Rick, what is Shangri-La? Maybe you could give us a little tour.
香格里拉是什么?
What is Shangri-La?
那是一个我们聚在一起玩耍的俱乐部。做记录。
It's a club house where we get together and play. Make records.
是的。
Yeah.
的更好。我想这就像办公室一样。
Kind of better. It's like an office, I guess.
这里以前是个妓院。
It used to be a bordello.
——一个妓院?-你可以从墙纸上看出来。
- A bordello? - You can tell by the wallpaper.
酒吧里的那种颓废，那种温柔。
That decadence, that softness in the barroom.
我听过一些有趣的故事。
I've heard a few funny stories, man.
-所以才会有这么多房间-你不能相信你所听到的。
- That's why all these rooms are here. - You can't believe most of what you hear.
这是一间主控制室，现在是一间主控制室。
This was a master-control bedroom, this is now a master-control music room.
我问你，现在《最后的华尔兹》已经结束了，你现在在做什么?
Let me ask you, now that The Last Waltz is over, what are you doing now?
艾迪，你为什么不…
Eddie, why don't you...
只是在做音乐，你知道吗?
Just making music, you know?
哦,是的。
Oh, yeah.
想让自己忙起来，伙计。
Trying to stay busy, man.
♪我想躺在你身边
♪ I want to lay down beside you
想将你的身体靠近我
♪ I want to hold your body close to mine
像成熟的葡萄…这是音乐带给你的。否则你永远不会陷入这样的境地。
♪ Like a grape that grows ripe... It's where the music took you. Otherwise you would never go to such a situation.
因为音乐，它带我们去任何地方。
Because of the music, it took us everywhere.
它把我们带到一些奇怪的地方。
It took us to some strange places.
-身体上和精神上?-身体上、精神上和精神上。
- Physically and spiritually? - Physically, spiritually and psychotically.
只是永远不会出现在舞台上。
It just always wasn't on the stage.
-即使你在舞台上。-即使我们在舞台上。
- Even though you were on the stage. - Even though we were on the stage.
♬她站在伟大的密西西比河畔♬独自在苍白的月光下等待一个男人，一个赌船的人♬说他今晚会回来
♪ She stands on the banks of the mighty Mississippi ♪ Alone in the pale moonlight ♪ Waiting for a man, a riverboat gambler ♪ Said that he'd return tonight
♬他们曾在伟大的密西西比河岸边跳着华尔兹♬整夜爱着♬直到河船上的赌徒去大赚一笔♬把它带给你
♪ They used to waltz on the banks of the mighty Mississippi ♪ Loving the whole night through ♪ Till the riverboat gambler went off to make a killing ♪ And bring it on back to you
诅咒密西西比皇后带走男人的灵魂
♪ Evangeline, Evangeline ♪ Curses the soul of the Mississippi Queen ♪ That pulled her man away
♪♪来自南路易斯安那州的山姆♪♪爱赌博是他的血脉♪♪伊万杰琳来自海洋♪♪他慢慢地疯了
♪ Bayou Sam from South Louisiana ♪ Had gambling in his veins ♪ Evangeline from the Maritimes ♪ Was slowly going insane
♪♪伫立在山核桃山顶♪♪在电闪雷鸣中，她伫立在河的下面，船正在下沉♪♪她看着王后沉入水中
♪ High on the top of Hickory Hill ♪ She stands in the lightning and thunder ♪ Down on the river the boat was sinking ♪ She watched that Queen go under
诅咒密西西比皇后带走男人的灵魂
♪ Evangeline, Evangeline ♪ Curses the soul of the Mississippi Queen ♪ That pulled her man away
加斯是我们认识的最了不起的音乐家之一。
Garth was one of the most amazing musicians that we knew.
他演奏得比我们听过的任何人都好。
He could play better than anybody we ever heard.
如果我们让加斯当音乐老师，他就能加入乐队。
And Garth joined The Band if we would make him the music teacher.
我们不知道为什么，但我们说:“当然可以。我的意思是，无论如何我们都很感兴趣。”
We didn't know why but we said "Sure. I mean, we're interested anyway."
我们不得不每周付给他10美元来上这些音乐课。
And we had to pay him $10 a week each for these music lessons.
然后我确定那只是一段重复。
Then I was sure it was a riff.
但后来我发现了它的真面目。
But then I found out what it really was.
那就是，他的出身和他的音乐教育背景，在这个时候告诉他的父母我们要加入一个摇滚乐队就像把一切都倒进了下水道。
It was that, where he was coming from and his musical education, to tell his parents at this point that we was joining a rock-and-roll band would have been like pouring it down the drain.
所以他以音乐教师的身份向他的人民和他的背景证明了这一点。
So he justified it to his people and his background by being a music teacher.
有一种观点认为爵士乐是邪恶的，因为它来自邪恶的人。
There is a view that jazz is evil because it comes from evil people.
但事实上，52街和纽约街头最伟大的牧师是音乐家。
But, actually, the greatest priests on 52nd Street and on the streets of New York City were the musicians.
他们在做最伟大的治疗工作。
They were doing the greatest healing work.
他们知道如何通过音乐来治愈并让人们感觉良好。
And they knew how to punch through music which would cure and make people feel good.
♬窗户上的板子♬门上的邮件♬为什么有人这么快就离开?
♪ Boards on the window ♪ Mail by the door ♪ Why would anybody leave so quickly for?
♪奥菲利娅
♪ Ophelia
♬你去了哪里?
♪ Where have you gone?
♪♪原来的街坊已经不一样了♪没人知道后来是什么♪奥菲莉亚
♪ The old neighbourhood just ain't the same ♪ Nobody knows just what became ♪ Of Ophelia
♬你去了哪里?
♪ Where have you gone?
♬是有人说了什么吗?
♪ Was it something that somebody said?
♬妈妈，你知道我们违反了规则
♪ Mama, you know we broke the rules
♬有人违反了法律吗?
♪ Was somebody up against the law?
♪♪亲爱的，你知道我愿意为你而死♪♪他们有你的号码♪他们害怕并奔跑♪但我只是在等待第二次降临♪奥菲莉亚
♪ Honey, you know that I'd die for you ♪ They got your number ♪ They're scared and running ♪ But I'm just waiting for the second coming ♪ Of Ophelia
♪请把我的门弄暗
♪ Please darken my door
♬是有人说了什么吗?
♪ Was it something that somebody said?
♬妈妈，你知道我们违反了规则
♪ Mama, you know we broke the rules
♬有人违反了法律吗?
♪ Was somebody up against the law?
♪哦，亲爱的，你知道我愿意为你而死♪笑声的灰烬♪幽灵很清晰♪为什么最好的东西总是会消失?
♪ Oh, honey, you know that I'd die for you ♪ Ashes of laughter ♪ The ghost is clear ♪ Why do the best things always disappear?
♪像欧菲莉亚
♪ Like Ophelia
♪哦，请回家吧
♪ Oh, please, come back home
不过，大部分的表演都像旅行表演，像帐篷表演。
Most of the show stuff, though, was like travelling shows, like tent shows.
一个是沃尔科特的兔脚吟游诗人。
One was Walcott's Rabbit Foot Minstrels.
-那是什么?-沃尔科特的兔脚吟游诗人是的。
- What was that? - Walcott's Rabbit Foot Minstrels. Yeah.
他们以前是让节目开场的，对吧?
They used to have the show start, right?
他们会有歌手、演员和节目的不同部分。
They'd have the singers and the players and the different parts of the show.
然后主持人会在最后一集之前出来解释说，孩子们回家后，他们会进行午夜漫步。
Then the master of ceremonies would come out just before the finale and explain that, after the kids go home, they'd have the midnight ramble.
——午夜……?-午夜漫步。
- The midnight...? - The midnight ramble.
歌曲会变得更有趣，笑话也会变得更有趣。
The songs would get a little bit juicier and the jokes'd get a little funnier.
最漂亮的舞者会跳下来，摇晃几下。
And the prettiest dancer would really get down and shake it a few times.
很多摇滚鸭子的走路、舞步和动作都来自于这些。
A lot of the rock-and-roll duck walks and steps and moves came from a lot of that.
每个人都这么做，所以，当你看到猫王、杰瑞·李·刘易斯、查克·贝里或波·迪德利真正改变世界的时候，它不是凭空而来的，不是凭空而来的。
Everybody did it and so, when you would see Elvis Presley or Jerry Lee Lewis or Chuck Berry or Bo Diddley really shaking it up, it didn't come out of nowhere, It didn't come out of the air.
这就像每个人都要去看的当地娱乐节目。
It was like the local entertainment everybody was going to see.
所以当他们把它展示给世界的时候，它就像一个未知的野兽出现了，这是魔鬼送来的怪异的音乐，你知道吗?
So when they exposed it to the rest of the world, it was like this unknown beast that had come out, the grotesque of music that the devil had sent, you know?
我们开始吧。
Here we go.
♬我能听到快乐的吉普赛人的演奏。♬妈妈，妈妈，看看艾玛·罗斯
♪ And the caravan is on its way ♪ I can hear the merry gypsies play ♪ Mama, Mama, look at Emma Rose
♬她在玩收音机♬啦啦啦啦啦啦♬啦啦啦啦啦
♪ She's a-playing with the radio ♪ La la la-la la-la la ♪ La la la-la la-la la ♪ And the caravan is painted red and white
♬这意味着每个人都要过夜♬光着脚的吉普赛男孩围着篝火又唱又玩一个女人告诉我们她的方式♬啦啦啦啦啦啦啦
♪ That means everybody's staying overnight ♪ And the barefoot gypsy boy round the campfire sing and play ♪ And a woman tells us of her ways ♪ La la la-la la-la la ♪ La la la-la la-la la
♬打开收音机
♪ Da da da-da da ♪ Turn up your radio
♪然后让我，让我，让我听听这首歌
♪ And let me, let me, let me hear the song ♪ Switch on your electric light
♬现在我们可以看看到底是什么问题了
♪ Now we can get down to what's really wrong
♪我多想拥你入怀，这样我就能，能感受到你的存在
♪ I long just to hold you in my arms ♪ So that I can, I can feel you
♪可爱的暗夜淑女
♪ Sweet lady of the night
♪♪我会让你知道♪♪打开点♪♪再大一点♪♪再大一点♪够了♪这样你就知道它有灵魂♪啦啦啦啦啦啦啦啦啦
♪ I shall reveal you ♪ Turn it up ♪ Turn it up ♪ Turn it up ♪ Little bit higher ♪ Radio ♪ Turn it up ♪ That's enough ♪ So you know it's got soul ♪ La la la-la la-la la ♪ La la la-la la-la la
♬打开收音机
♪ Turn up your radio
让我，让我，让我，让我听听这首歌
♪ And let me, let me, let me, let me hear the song
♬打开电灯
♪ Switch on your electric light
♪我渴望能拥你入怀，这样我就能，我就能感受到你
♪ Then we can get down to what's really wrong, really wrong, really wrong ♪ I long just to hold you in my arms ♪ So that I can, I can feel you
♪夜晚的小姐♪我将向你揭示♪打开点♪再打开点♪再高一点♪收音机再打开点♪这就够了♪所以你知道♪这是有灵魂的♪所以你知道
♪ Sweet lady of the night ♪ I shall reveal you ♪ Turn it up ♪ Turn it up ♪ Turn it up ♪ Little bit higher ♪ Radio ♪ Turn it up ♪ That's enough ♪ So you know ♪ It's got soul ♪ So you know
♪所以你知道它有♪的灵魂，宝贝
♪ So you know it's got ♪ Soul, baby
♪所以你知道它有♪是的
♪ So you know it's got ♪ Yeah
♬你知道它有灵魂
♪ Zi boo ba boogie, zi boo ba boogie, zi boo ba boogie ♪ So you know it's got soul
♪所以你知道它除了灵魂什么都没有
♪ So you know it's got nothin♪ but soul
♬现在打开♬耶，耶，耶，再来一次
♪ Turn it up now ♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah ♪ One more time
♬再做一次♬你知道了
♪ Do that one more time ♪ So you know
♬再做一次
♪ Do that one more time
♬再做一次♬再做一次♬再做一次
♪ Do that one more time ♪ One more ♪ Do that one more time
♬再做一次谢谢。
♪ Do that one more time Thank you.
嘿，Van the Man!
Hey, Van the Man!
劳伦斯Ferlinghetti !
Lawrence Ferlinghetti!
让我们祈祷。
Let us pray.
我们的天父，以你的名义在天堂，除非事情改变。
Our Father, whose art's in heaven Hollow by thy name - unless things change.
你的智慧来了又去。
Thy wigdom come and gone.
你的意志，将在地上被摧毁，因为那不是天堂。
Thy will, will be undone on earth, as it isn't heaven.
让我们每天都感到恐惧，一天至少三次。
Give us this day our daily dread, at least three times a day.
原谅我们在爱的领地上的僭越。
And forgive us our trespasses on love's territory.
因为你是上帝的化身、权力和荣耀……哦,男人!
For thine is the wigdom and power and glory... Oh, man!
♪愿上帝保佑并与你同在
♪ May God bless and keep you always
♪愿你永远为别人做什么，也让别人为你做什么
♪ May your wishes all come true ♪ May you always do for others ♪ And let others do for you
♪愿你筑起通往星空的梯子♪爬上每一个横档♪愿你留下
♪ May you build a ladder to the stars ♪ Climb on every rung ♪ And may you stay
♪永远年轻
♪ Forever young
♪♪永远年轻
♪ Forever young ♪ Forever young
♪愿你永远年轻
♪ May you stay ♪ Forever young
♪愿你的手永远忙碌♪愿你的脚永远敏捷♪愿你在变化的风向转变时拥有坚实的基础
♪ May your hands always be busy ♪ May your feet always be swift ♪ May you have a strong foundation when the winds of changes shift
♪愿你的心永远快乐♪愿你的歌永远被唱♪愿你永远年轻
♪ May your heart always be joyful ♪ May your song always be sung ♪ And may you stay ♪ Forever young
♪永远年轻
♪ Forever young
♪愿你永远年轻
♪ May you stay ♪ Forever young
♬我能和你一起回家吗?
♪ Can I come home with you?
宝贝，我能和你一起回家吗?
♪ Baby, can I come home with you?
♪。我会做任何事♪。只要你让我和你一起回家
♪ Well, I'll do anything in this god-almighty world ♪ if you'll just let me come home with you
♬宝贝，让我追随你♬宝贝，让我追随你♬如果你让我追随你，我愿做任何事
♪ Baby, let me follow you down ♪ Baby, let me follow you down ♪ Well, I'll do anything in this god-almighty world ♪ if you'll just let me follow you down
♪。我会给你买钻戒♪。我会给你买婚纱♪。好吧，在这个万能的世界上我愿意做任何事♪。只要你让我跟随你
♪ I'll buy you a diamond ring ♪ I'll buy you a wedding gown ♪ Well, I'll do anything in this god-almighty world ♪ if you'll just let me follow you down
谢谢你！
Thank you.
林戈和罗尼·伍德这次也会帮我们。
We got Ringo and Ronnie Wood gonna help us out on this one, too.
♪。他们说什么都可以被替换
♪ They say everything can be replaced
♪。他们说每一段距离都是遥不可及的
♪ They say every distance is not near
♪所以我记得每一张脸
♪ So I remember every face
♪。每一个把我弄到这里的人
♪ Of every man who put me here
♪我看见自己的光在闪耀
♪ I see my light come shining
♬从西到东
♪ From the west down to the east
♪♪任何一天我都会被释放
♪ Any day now ♪ Any day now ♪ I shall be released
人们说每个男人都需要保护
♪ They say every man needs protection
♪有人说每个人都会跌倒
♪ They say that every man must fall
♪但我发誓我看见了自己的倒影
♪ But I swear I see my reflection
♬某个高过这堵墙的地方
♪ Somewhere so high above this wall
♪我看见自己的光在闪耀
♪ I see my light come shining
♬从西到东
♪ From the west down to the east
♪♪任何一天我都会被释放
♪ Any day now ♪ Any day now ♪ I shall be released
♪在这孤独的人群中
♪ Down here in this lonely crowd
有一个人发誓不怪他
♪ There's a man who swears he's not to blame
♪我整天听见他大声喊叫
♪ All day long I hear him shouting loud
♬哭诉自己是被陷害的
♪ Crying out that he been framed
♪我看见我的光照耀♪从西到东
♪ I see my light come shining ♪ From the west down to the east
♪♪任何一天我都会被释放
♪ Any day now ♪ Any day now ♪ I shall be released
——谢谢。-非常感谢。
- Thank you. - Thank you very much.
那条路就是我们的学校。它给了我们一种生存的感觉。
The road was our school. It gave us a sense of survival.
它教会了我们所知道的一切。
It taught us all we know.
我们能从路上带走的东西已经不多了。
There's not much left that we can really take from the road.
我们已经有了我们的一份……或者这只是迷信。
We've had our share of... Or maybe it's just superstitious.
-哪种迷信?你可以碰运气。
- Superstitious in what way? - You can press your luck.
这条路走了很多伟大的道路。
The road has taken a lot of the great ones.
汉克威廉姆斯。巴迪·霍利。Otis Redding。
Hank Williams. Buddy Holly. Otis Redding.
詹尼斯。吉米·亨德里克斯。
Janis. Jimi Hendrix.
猫王。
Elvis.
这是一种他妈的不可能的生活方式。
It's a goddamn impossible way of life.
-是的，不是吗?-毫无疑问。
- It is, isn't it? - No question about it.